[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbd", "question": "What famous museum was once called the Musee' Napoleon?", "answer": "The Louvre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba4", "question": "What country is located immediately north of Sudan?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939e", "question": "Which 1993 movie is subtitled: \"The Bruce Lee Story\"?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f65101dd7bf43be5e831", "question": "What was the only NBA team Michael Jordan played for other than the Chicago Bulls?", "answer": "Washington Wizzards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b64", "question": "What was the name of Danny's gang on the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The Thunderbirds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c345", "question": "What metal is also known as quicksilver?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a890", "question": "What city is home to The Willis Tower?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590721e13745b36be73039fb", "question": "Which Disney character is named after Ebenezer from Charles Dickens\u2019 novel \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "Scrooge McDuck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962a", "question": "In what movie does Alec Baldwin play a ghost?", "answer": "Beetle Juice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca0", "question": "When do \"blue laws\" prohibit certain activities?", "answer": "On Sundays", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7decff048f679a45ac02", "question": "Aphenphosmphobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Being touched", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ad", "question": "In what city would you find Griffith Park?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72d1aad0874f1a5e2d1c2c", "question": "What band has the most No. 1 hits on \"The Billboard Hot 100\" with 20 songs to reach No. 1?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fcddfe83fe1f2a824c46", "question": "Which scientist patented new ballet shoes to protect dancers\u2019 feet?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d84", "question": "What miraculous transformation does the Devil first tempt Jesus to try in the wilderness?", "answer": "Turning stones into bread", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66bdba5bfecdd737e088a", "question": "What is the only bird to have its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd3747e83c707845b2153", "question": "What is the name of the prequel to \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "\"Red Dragon\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad60", "question": "The 2008 Summer Olympic Games were held in what city?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b983", "question": "The synodic month starts with a new what?", "answer": "Moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab65", "question": "What links Catalonia, Andalusia, Cantabria, Galicia?", "answer": "They are regions of Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f6f36a9e54d890926f6cf", "question": "Which U.S. state has an official state cookie called biscochito?", "answer": "New Mexico -- Brought to the\u00a0region by 16th-century Spanish colonists, it is a shortbread cookie flavored with cinnamon and anise.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b78", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Cat on a Hot Tin Roof\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa9", "question": "What is the capital of the Federated States of Micronesia?", "answer": "Palikir", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a125", "question": "What do \"Tom\", \"Dick\", and \"Harry\" refer to in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "The escape tunnels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d74", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"There and Back Again\"?", "answer": "The Hobbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bd93d96d05b23b28165d", "question": "What were the earliest forms of contraceptive made from?", "answer": "Crocodile dung", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e36", "question": "What game show host took his stage name from the college in his West Virginia hometown?", "answer": "Peter Marshall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b76b01dd7bf43be5e7e4", "question": "What did the Colgate company originally sell?", "answer": "Soap and candles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb2087e83c707845b2110", "question": "A group of lizards is called what?", "answer": "A lounge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86c", "question": "In a game of Hearts, what term describes winning every heart and the queen of spades?", "answer": "Shooting the Moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b6990cae762b54eb9be9414", "question": "How old was Janet Leigh in her debut film \"The Romance of Rosy Ridge\"?", "answer": "20", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79e", "question": "How many moons does the planet Neptune have?", "answer": "14", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c34", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba44", "question": "The philanthropist, Andrew Carnegie, made his fortune in what industry?", "answer": "Steel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b52806d333868d34d6e6", "question": "Captain Henry Morgan used what island as a base of buccaneer operations?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6c", "question": "What letter of the alphabet do IATA airport codes for Canada begin with?", "answer": "Y", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc4", "question": "Pan was half man, half what?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0b", "question": "What former US president founded the University of Virginia?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60077f38bd51d85e222ab63c", "question": "In biology, a relationship between individuals of two species in which one species obtains food or other benefits from the other without either harming or benefiting the latter is called what?", "answer": "Commensalism (An example is where barnacles live on some whales and benefit by having a place to live and feed, while the whale is not harmed, but derives no benefit.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339120", "question": "What year saw the release of H. G. Wells' \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "1895", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ee", "question": "Gastroenteritis is the inflammation of what?", "answer": "Stomach and intestines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dca", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Willie Garvin?", "answer": "Modesty Blaise", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0aa", "question": "Who won an oscar for her role in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Vivien Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ca", "question": "For what crime was Bruno Hauptmann executed in 1936?", "answer": "Kidnapping the Lindbergh baby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59bb28bdc9bff04efae6d753", "question": "What year was Mario Puzo's novel \"The Godfather\" published?", "answer": "1969", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b84", "question": "What cathedral was the fictional Quasimodo a bell ringer for?", "answer": "Notre Dame", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c830", "question": "What hinged surfaces on a plane's wingtips allow the aircraft to roll?", "answer": "Ailerons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6698aa5bfecdd737e087c", "question": "What color was Mario's shirt in his very first video game appearance?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b026", "question": "What Native American leader surrendered at Skeleton Canyon in 1886?", "answer": "Geronimo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d1164d4fea7fe947a2226e", "question": "What year was the film \"The Fly\", starring Jeff Goldblum, released in theaters?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae04", "question": "Who was Erik Weisz better known as?", "answer": "Harry Houdini", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd664a5a5bfecdd737e0857", "question": "How many people survived the Titanic sinking?", "answer": "706", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c6", "question": "What year did Edward Jenner introduce the world's first successful vaccine?", "answer": "1796", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c830fbde8045e48466d2", "question": "What scientist proposed the theory of continental drift?", "answer": "Alfred Wegener", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a980561d1b4d384d5d68b", "question": "Boise is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b4", "question": "In which country will you find most of the Aral sea in?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd9de7e83c707845b217e", "question": "In the game of golf, the iconic \"Green Jacket\" is presented to the winner of which championship?", "answer": "Masters Tournament", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a50d20565ad31a57c7c6", "question": "Who was the first American woman on a U.S. postage stamp?", "answer": "Martha Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af13", "question": "What city hosted the Winter Olympics in 1932?", "answer": "Lake Placid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907d", "question": "What controversial book did Germaine Greer write?", "answer": "The Female Eunuch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990f369fa5fdd6dd25324da", "question": "Which film producer said \"Anyone who goes to a psychiatrist ought to have his head examined\"?", "answer": "Samuel Goldwyn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93ac66bd93ce3a4e5f69b", "question": "What is the scientific study of animal biology?", "answer": "Zoology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4f", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Amazing Grace and Chuck\"?", "answer": "Alex English", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8a92301dd7bf43be5e748", "question": "Who is the patron saint of lost causes?", "answer": "St. Jude", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfaebcf3977a46e7ce448", "question": "Bees have 5 what?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ae", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24e", "question": "Who had a hit with the song \"Jacob's Ladder\"?", "answer": "Huey Lewis and the News", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3235b4bf195a31e15d73b2", "question": "What is a system of circulating ocean currents referred to as?", "answer": "A Gyre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7e65ff048f679a45ac0d", "question": "Barophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60a", "question": "What is an alloy?", "answer": "A metal mixed with an element", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a23b6c0f9723ab15cb40", "question": "How long was the Mayflower's journey to the New World?", "answer": "66 days", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c511", "question": "What are deheaded, deveined and sorted by size in a Laitram machine?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c807", "question": "What grapefruit-sized object has been reckoned to be the largest single cell on earth?", "answer": "An ostrich egg yolk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be5", "question": "What two kinds of opera do the Arts recognize?", "answer": "Comic and Grand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c1", "question": "In atmospheres, what is the equivalent of 760 milimeters of Mercury (mmHg)?", "answer": "1 atm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c4", "question": "What is the technical term for egg white?", "answer": "Albumen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc1573469bb8041d07a08b", "question": "What London landmark did Queen Elizabeth II open up to tourism in 1993?", "answer": "Buckingham Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c737", "question": "What does a lepidopterist study or collect?", "answer": "Butterflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cd40c41685cf15b733e988d", "question": "Which cartoon family lives in 31 Spooner Street, Quahog, Rhode Island, USA?", "answer": "The Griffins (Family Guy)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c85dfbde8045e48466d7", "question": "What is Johannes Kepler best known for?", "answer": "Kepler's laws of planetary motion are three scientific laws describing the motion of planets around the Sun.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c668", "question": "What falcon is the fastest bird in North America?", "answer": "Peregrine Falcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ba", "question": "Which is the world's northernmost capital city?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abee", "question": "What is the capital of Ukraine?", "answer": "Kiev", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00c", "question": "Who gave the famous \"Keep Hope Alive\" speech at the 1988 Democratic National Convention?", "answer": "Jesse Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029d60cad1ec93f27df74d", "question": "Where did Thomas Lipton open his first grocery store?", "answer": "Glasgow, Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b865", "question": "What is the only bird to be honored by its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339408", "question": "Who directed the 2003 movie \"Monster\"?", "answer": "Patty Jenkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93b5c6bd93ce3a4e5f6a3", "question": "What did Evangelista Torricelli invent?", "answer": "Mercury barometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a6b720565ad31a57c7dd", "question": "The aircraft carrier USS Lexington was lost in which World War II battle?", "answer": "The Battle of the Coral Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c854", "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea46c3ff048f679a45aba5", "question": "The diameter of an atom is measured in which units?", "answer": "Angstroms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339872", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", what does the bottle marked \"Drink Me\" do?", "answer": "Shrinks you", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36f", "question": "What body of water does the Danube River flow into?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b59", "question": "In what year did rapper Tupac Shakur die?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af50", "question": "What happened on September 1, 1939 that led to Britain and France declaring war on Germany?", "answer": "Invasion of Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ff", "question": "What Poker hand comprises three of a kind and a pair?", "answer": "A full house", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc8428378d18506ae1fe48c", "question": "Who was the front for the British band \"Dire Straits\"?", "answer": "Mark Knopfler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe51ece1bf59ab7d2e380e2", "question": "Who was responsible for the introduction of the Ford Mustang in 1964?", "answer": "Lee Iacocca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae92a7574a5ce6b56b8230", "question": "Who wrote the play \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c029", "question": "What sport is sometimes called rugger?", "answer": "Rugby union", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a67", "question": "Who wrote the children's book \"The Trumpet of the Swan\"?", "answer": "E.B. White", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338920", "question": "What spice is the most essential and valuable commodity in the \"Dune\" universe?", "answer": "Melange", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338884", "question": "What Hebrew word means \"so be it\"?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d20", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Tin Cup\"?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906814dff9c0647b50a8093", "question": "How old was novelist Harper Lee at the time of her death in February, 2016?", "answer": "89", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c399", "question": "An \"atomizer\" is a device most often used to distribute what?", "answer": "Perfume", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339244", "question": "What movie was hyped: \"Girls like me don't make invitations like this to just anyone\"?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba82", "question": "What was the first American company to manufacture color TV sets in the US?", "answer": "RCA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff4", "question": "Guru Nanak founded which religion?", "answer": "Sikhism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62b", "question": "What river flows along the southern border of South Carolina?", "answer": "Savannah River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f38", "question": "What was the first rap single to hit number one on Billboard's Hot 100?", "answer": "Ice Ice Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81c98d0de9af39e9d4686", "question": "What U.S. president was nicknamed \"Napoleon of the Stump?\"", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d5", "question": "What US state name ends with three vowels?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a970", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named the Diet?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f1", "question": "Salton Sea is located in which western US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e6", "question": "In what city is Gonzaga University located?", "answer": "Spokane, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b454", "question": "Where did Abraham Lincoln give his historic speech?", "answer": "Gettysburg, Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b8", "question": "Who directed the 1980 movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "John Landis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6f", "question": "What are described by the terms rep, challis and foulard?", "answer": "Neckties", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987a", "question": "In Star Wars, where is Princess Leia from?", "answer": "Alderaan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab92a0b8cce1e6fda7053", "question": "The most popular car color in the USA for 2019 was which color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab31d0b8cce1e6fda7042", "question": "What celebrity had their dog cloned, twice?", "answer": "Barbara Streisand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0f", "question": "What was Wayne Gretzky's jersey number during his professional hockey career?", "answer": "99", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb0875acf631c2414a13b56", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what are the three names of Daenerys\u2019 dragons?", "answer": "Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10a", "question": "What name is given to the diagram in which sets are represented by circles?", "answer": "Venn Diagram\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b171", "question": "What year was the Brooklyn Bridge designated as a National Historic Landmark?", "answer": "1964", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339603", "question": "What movie coined the phrase \"In space, no one can hear you scream\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397af", "question": "What television show's theme was played at the commissioning of the first space shuttle?", "answer": "Star Trek's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133badd", "question": "What country won the men\u2019s World Cup in soccer in 2010?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a036", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", what does Quagmire do in an attempt to get out of his marriage?", "answer": "Fake his own death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339582", "question": "What movie takes place on February 2nd again and again?", "answer": "Groundhog Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1c", "question": "What TV show's announcer was Hank \"Hey Now!\" Kingsley?", "answer": "The Larry Sanders Show's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c802fbde8045e48466cc", "question": "What is a body's resistance to changes in motion or speed called?", "answer": "Inertia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3dbb44f0f6af5b06663e", "question": "What is the capital of Andorra?", "answer": "Andorra la Vella", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e3f5d35cb9e8bda682136b", "question": "Samuel Miller patented the first steam-powered what in 1806?", "answer": "Drill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c5", "question": "In badminton, what is hit over the net?", "answer": "A shuttlecock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b0", "question": "If you were infected with the variola virus, what disease did you have?", "answer": "Smallpox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11d", "question": "In what year did Aaron Burr kill Alexander Hamilton in a duel?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b673", "question": "What term was coined in 1983 to market the \"Gavilan SC\" portable computer?", "answer": "Laptop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16690f7c52aae91cc07af", "question": "What is New Year's Eve called in Scotland?", "answer": "Hogmanay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b5", "question": "With which hand do soldiers salute?", "answer": "Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90a", "question": "What year did the famous Sears Tower in Chicago had its name changed to the \"Willis Tower\"?", "answer": "2009", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba89", "question": "In what year did the NBA introduce the 24 \u00adsecond shot clock?", "answer": "1954", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e7d438e4e5d4832e6308", "question": "To prevent German pilots from successfully bombing Great Britain at night, British citizens were required to do what?", "answer": "Prevent any light from escaping their homes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5611c73aa70ea0b70b27", "question": "In which country is May Day the only holiday workers are obliged to be given the day off yet still be paid for it?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b7", "question": "In which US state are the Catskill Mountains located?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08d", "question": "Who hosted the 1997 Grammy Awards?", "answer": "Ellen Degeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b507", "question": "What is tripe on a menu?", "answer": "Stomach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeaa", "question": "Which German Nazi was known as the butcher of Lyon?", "answer": "Klaus Barbie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85f", "question": "Which car company produced a model named the Celica?", "answer": "Toyota", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe658f9ae7e414034b5aef8", "question": "Who designed the first Christmas card?", "answer": "J.C. Horsely", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d1", "question": "What year did tennis player Martina Navratilova turn pro?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f9", "question": "In the 1986 movie \"Labyrinth\", what disguise does the King of the Goblins visits Sarah's house under?", "answer": "An owl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5d", "question": "What's the traditional meat on a Reuben sandwich?", "answer": "Corned beef", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc10", "question": "Whose jersey number 99 was retired by all teams in the NHL following his career retirement?", "answer": "Wayne Gretzky's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e259fe83fe1f2a824b9e", "question": "Via what route did Russians manage to send some supplies to Leningrad during the German siege of the city?", "answer": "A supply route across Lake Ladoga", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a313", "question": "What year did MTV debut as a channel?", "answer": "1981", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cd40ba5685cf15b733e988b", "question": "In which county in the United Kingdom is the Glastonbury Festival held?", "answer": "Somerset", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339300", "question": "What song does Ferris Bueller sing from the float in the Chicago parade?", "answer": "Twist and Shout", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd59dd0499cffc60b8422a", "question": "What was the last Province to join Canada?", "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1bb0baab681b0929219b", "question": "Which Canadian city is host to the Canadian International Autoshow?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae866977f28483af1e7fdd4", "question": "What is the name of the musician best known for his 1993 song \"What is Love\"?", "answer": "Haddaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac35", "question": "Which of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World was alive?", "answer": "The Hanging Gardens of Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338882", "question": "Who was the fairy in Peter Pan?", "answer": "Tinkerbelle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4df1c06d333868d34d71e", "question": "What is the name of the eon we are living in?", "answer": "Phanerozoic Eon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb01", "question": "What is the chemical element Azote now referred to as?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc0e8f469bb8041d07a061", "question": "What is a word having same spelling but different sound and meaning?", "answer": "Heteronym", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5c716ce05a3942286e20", "question": "Which actress keeps her Oscar in her bathroom so guests can hold it and make speeches in the mirror shame-free?", "answer": "Kate Winslet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002435d4be4723ccac22195", "question": "In William Shakespeare\u2019s \"A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream\", what is the name of the King of the Fairies?", "answer": "Oberon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c4", "question": "If you suffer from epistaxis what is wrong?", "answer": "Your nose is bleeding", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb2a52c9bff04efae6d75f", "question": "What is the birthname of author George Orwell?", "answer": "Eric Arthur Blair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b245", "question": "In 2002, Sony ended production of its recorders using what doomed video standard?", "answer": "Betamax", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b5717d767df192a942e3359", "question": "What significance does the number 4468 have to trainspotters?", "answer": "Marks the 4468 Mallard, the fastest steam locomotive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb9907e83c707845b213b", "question": "A group of hippopotamuses is called what?", "answer": "A bloat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ef", "question": "What US state has been governed by John Connally and Ann Richards?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071f8a3745b36be73039eb", "question": "The comic book series \"Revival\" is often described as what literary genre?", "answer": "Horror/Rural-noir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c08f", "question": "What was a Nuremberg egg?", "answer": "A small clock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who learned medicine at \"The Hollywood Upstairs Medical School\"?", "answer": "Dr. Nick Riviera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339232", "question": "Who played the Cook County Assessor's Office Clerk in \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a63520565ad31a57c7d4", "question": "What was the name of the first operational nuclear-powered submarine?", "answer": "USS Nautilus SSN-571", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f7d", "question": "What was Bruce Hornsby's backing band?", "answer": "The Range", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb675c5dad637d903c883d", "question": "According to its former minister of tourism, which country is known abroad for its three Rs: reggae, romance and running?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c611877e98cb977789b4", "question": "Which US state is home to the Valley of Fire?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a74d", "question": "Which US state is home to the Catskill Mountains?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5901da79709c1c34536e6eaf", "question": "In ice hockey, how many players for each team are allowed on the ice at the same time?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4a", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Star Trek: The Motion Picture\"?", "answer": "Persis Khambatta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc131ec223966ae8f8866", "question": "Michael Jordan hit his famous 1998 \"Last Shot\" over what Utah Jazz player?", "answer": "Byron Russell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29e", "question": "What fraction pure is 18-carat gold?", "answer": "Three-quarters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5be5816b5415ba52ed6f0ac1", "question": "What is the study of pronunciation called?", "answer": "Orthoepy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c800", "question": "By what common name is sodium bicarbonate otherwise known?", "answer": "Baking Soda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc1316ce05a3942286f10", "question": "In the original television series \"Hawaii Five-O,\" who stared as Detective Steve McGarrett?", "answer": "Jack Lord", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14563b0ee8c595b6d39b9", "question": "What play's full title includes \"A Trivial Comedy for Serious People\"?", "answer": "\"The Importance of Being Earnest\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c1", "question": "On what continent would you find the Great Victoria Desert?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb0", "question": "Which US coast is the state of Maryland located on?", "answer": "East", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e5", "question": "Who directed the film \"Serpico\"?", "answer": "Sidney Lumet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd3a877e98cb97778a33", "question": "Where is the lowest freshwater lake by altitude in the world?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6584eae7e414034b5aeec", "question": "How many dogs survived the sinking of the Titanic?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6000ee019a72b906b34e3cf3", "question": "Which part of the body is affected by blepharitis?", "answer": "Eyelids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf0", "question": "What fitness program did Judi Sheppard Missett create in 1969?", "answer": "Jazzercise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad9", "question": "Edmonton is the capital of which Canadian province?", "answer": "Alberta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb2", "question": "Which German city was the birthplace of the poet Heinrich Heine?", "answer": "Dusseldorf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d1", "question": "Billed as \"The Crime of the Century\", in which US city did the Great Brink's Robbery take place, in 1950?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bd", "question": "The first satellites to visit Venus, Mars, & Mercury were all named what?", "answer": "Mariner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3d33c73aa70ea0b70af4", "question": "Who was the state Louisiana named after?", "answer": "King Louis XIV of France -- Explorer Ren\u00e9-Robert Cavelier named the area to honor his king. \"La Louisiane\" translates to \"Land of Louis\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b740", "question": "Who is widely credited as being the inventor of the modern commercially available toilet paper?", "answer": "Joseph Gayetty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a681", "question": "What lake is located between Lake Huron and Lake Erie?", "answer": "Lake St. Clair", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b7", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives is buried beside him?", "answer": "Jane Seymour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e082fe83fe1f2a824b8e", "question": "Who won the first Nobel Prize for Medicine?", "answer": "Emil von Behring", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e94e67ccba3ffe45786da", "question": "What language was the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "FLOW-MATIC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a6e", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Electric Kool-Aid Acid Test\"?", "answer": "Tom Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc8421e78d18506ae1fe48a", "question": "What is the name of the tallest tree in the world?", "answer": "Hyperion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339695", "question": "Who starred as Achilles in the 2004 movie \"Troy\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a4", "question": "What fruit is grown extensively on Cape Cod?", "answer": "Cranberries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f68a01dd7bf43be5e832", "question": "What are the holes in Swiss cheese called?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede1156ce05a3942286dc1", "question": "Which state is \"Almost Heaven\"?", "answer": "West Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ab", "question": "In the world of music how is \"Harry Lillis\" more commonly known?", "answer": "Bing Crosby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4a", "question": "Gangster Al Capone was eventually arrested and convicted on what charge?", "answer": "Tax evasion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be74", "question": "Who were the winners of the James E. Sullivan Award for amateur athletics in 1986 and 1988?", "answer": "Jackie Joyner-Kersee and Florence Griffith-Joyner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7dd", "question": "Which Canadian provinces are known as the \"Maritime Provinces\"?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99c0121a8909e5c332d32", "question": "What year did Gary K. Wolf publish the novel \"Who Censored Roger Rabbit?\"?", "answer": "1981", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1d", "question": "In the nursery rhyme what is Friday's child?", "answer": "Loving and Giving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9f", "question": "What two pieces are moved in chess to execute a castling maneuver?", "answer": "King and rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a672", "question": "The city of Albuquerque is located in what desert?", "answer": "Chihuahua Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a6", "question": "How many Academy Awards did the 1939 movie \"Gone With The Wind\" win?", "answer": "10", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febae847e83c707845b20f6", "question": "Which insect uses the Milky Way to navigate?", "answer": "African dung beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1d", "question": "What year saw the release of Disney's animated movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "1950", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf4", "question": "What disorder did Muhammad Ali develop after retiring from boxing?", "answer": "Parkinson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a441", "question": "Which ancient site in the mountains of Peru is known as \"The Lost City of the Incas\"?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a7", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for a Scottish village?", "answer": "Strontium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3a", "question": "Which of the TV's \"Golden Girls\" plays the title character in \"Stop! Or My Mom Will Shoot\"?", "answer": "Estelle Getty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728c486bcd28c119383283", "question": "What reference book went on sale for the first time in 1955?", "answer": "The Guinness Book of Records", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ae863cc7f28483af1e7fdcc", "question": "How many territories does India have?", "answer": "7", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b841", "question": "What do the S, V, and P stand for in RSVP?", "answer": "S'il vous plait", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa8", "question": "What flavor of schnapps is used to make the drink Fuzzy Navel?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a553253e1c6f9840ba31a1", "question": "Which female trio won 5 Grammy Awards in 2007?", "answer": "The Dixie Chicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b7", "question": "In what movie did Charlie Sheen play the character Bud Fox?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1936682715b82711ce2", "question": "The fear of fire is known as what?", "answer": "Pyrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bce", "question": "Which pair of German brothers collected such stories as \"Hansel & Gretel\"?", "answer": "The Brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c077", "question": "Which English word is a combination of the first 2 letters of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Alphabet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7e95fb24f84e0b9f9ffcd", "question": "Seretse Khama was the first President of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdabcbc0b8cce1e6fda705f", "question": "Which food can be called \"marrowfat\"?", "answer": "Processed peas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a346", "question": "What song contains the lyrics \"Whatever happened to my Transylvania twist\"?", "answer": "The Monster Mash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3c", "question": "What \"Animal House\" actor made his show-biz debut as the voice of TV's Jonny Quest?", "answer": "Tim Matheson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bccf", "question": "What fruit is most commonly added to yogurt to make Indian \"raita\"?", "answer": "Cucumber", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0c0b469bb8041d07a04c", "question": "What is the official flower of Easter?", "answer": "White Lilly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c272", "question": "What is April's birthstone?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a98e361d1b4d384d5d693", "question": "Which major lake is near the Ponderosa Ranch in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078c5a0eee65b76b9f2672", "question": "Who became vice president of the U.S. after President Nixon resigned?", "answer": "Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbf", "question": "What model was married to musician Tommy Lee?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e0", "question": "In The Simpsons who said: \"I got a home remedy that'll put the zowzers back in your trousers.\"?", "answer": "Abe SImpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d6aa2b42d4a3561a9f06", "question": "West Swan is a suburb in which Australian city?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893e", "question": "What armless statue in the Louvre is described as \"the most famous work of art of the ancient Greek sculpture\"?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af9858caeb0982ee455954e", "question": "Which physical force is the only one that is always attractive, never repulsive?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}]